David Sanderson

Software Engineer

Professional Summary

Albuquerque-based Fullstack Developer with a strong passion for designing, building, and deploying custom websites/software applications. Most familiar with React but also proficient with Node, Express, C#, CSS, HTML and willing to learn new technologies . Resilient and curious problem solver with 4 years of development experience, excellent interpersonal skills, and the tenacity to solve difficult problems.

Experience

Software Engineer, Product & Engineering @ Meow Wolf

April 2021 - present // Albuquerque, NM

Technologies used: NextJS, Gatsby, Typescript, Jest, GQL, Vercel, Tailwind, Ticketure

- Leverage front-end technologies to develop whimsical and imaginative web experiences.
- Collaborate with various stakeholders (designers, product management, qa, data engineering) to plan and create web applications that are functional, performant, and bring joy to our users.
- Maintain and regularly implement new features on internal and customer-facing web applications.

Jr. Software Engineer @ iTeam Consulting

February 2020 - April 2021 // Albuquerque, NM

<u>Technologies used:</u> Gatsby, Git, React, C#, SharePoint, Jest, Tailwind, Bootstrap, Netlify,

Active Directory, Exchange, O365, Azure, various ORMs

- Migrate multiple legacy websites to the JAM stack using GatsbyJS.
- Maintain and regularly update legacy ASP.NET Web applications (MVC 5.0 and Razor Pages).
- Dimplement designs I create or am provided in Figma.
- > Created a Gatsby application that sources data from Sharepoint Lists to programmatically create web pages.

Resident Web Developer @ Activate New Mexico

October 2019 - February 2020 // Albuquerque, NM

Technologies used: React, Gatsby, GQL, WordPress, MySQL, MySQL Workbench

- Provided technical support and consultation to early-stage startups.
- Draft and execute project charters.
- Created 3 websites for participating startups.
- Conducted database design for a health-care startup.



davidsanderson.dev



github.com/d-sanderson



sanderdj90@gmail.com



505-604-5355



linkedin.com/in/d-sanderson

Skills

Programming Languages

JavaScript (ES6), Typescript, C#, HTML, CSS/ SCSS

Libraries and Frameworks

React, Gatsby, Next, Node.js, Cypress, Jest, Tailwind, Emotion

Tools and Platforms

Git, Vercel, Netlify CMS, Docker, Airtable, GraphQL

Design

Figma, Responsive Design

Education

University of New Mexico

2008 - 2013 // Albuquerque, NM Bachelors of Science - Evolutionary Anthropology

Amy Biehl High School

2004 - 2008 // Albuquerque, NM High School Diploma Studied website design

Certifications

- C# Fundamentals
- Testing .NET Code with xUnit
- CNM Ingenuity Cert. of Completion -Fullstack Bootcamp October 2018

Current Projects

Exploring the Transitions API and XState